Guide to the John Wesley Hardin Papers
The Wittliff Collections
- Correspondence, 1874-1895, undated
  - 1889-1893 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Oct 29, 1893. J.W. Hardin to J.G. Smither
    Nov 5, 1893. J.W. Hardin to W.S. Fly
    [unknown] Nannie Hardin to [Unknown]
    [unknown] [J.W. Hardin] to State of Texas[unknown]
    [Unknown] to [Unknown]
  - 1894 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    [unknown, 1894] J.W. Hardin to [Unknown]
    [unknown] D.C. Price & Co. to [Unknown]
    Jan 1, 1894. J.W. Hardin to Governor J.S. Hogg
    Jan 2, 1894. Callie Lewis to J.W. Hardin
    Jan 9, 1894. J.D. McCall to K.R. Blackshear
    Jan 28, 1894. J.S. Hardin to J.W. Hardin
    [Feb, 1894] Barnett Gibbs to J.W. Hardin
    Feb 7, 1894. K.R. Blackshear to J.G. Smither
    Feb 28, 1894. R.M. Glover to J.W. Hardin
    Mar 6, 1894. J.B. Ashe to J.W. Hardin
    Mar 8, 1894. J.D. Long to J.W. Hardin
    Mar 27, 1894. Tom Bell to R.M. Glover
    Mar 28, 1894. R.M. Glover to J.W. Hardin
    Mar 30, 1894. Tom Bell to R.M. Glover & R.M. Glover to J.W. Hardin
    Apr 13, 1894. R.M. Glover to J.W. Hardin
    Apr 14, 1894. F.D. Bishop to J.W. Hardin
    Apr 14, 1894. Tom Bell to R.M. Glover
    Apr 16, 1894. R.M. Glover to J.W. Hardin
    [Apr, 1894] R.W. Finley to J.W. Hardin
    Apr 28, 1894. J.M. Taylor to J.W. Hardin
    May 9, 1894. J.P. Randle to J.W. Hardin
    May 20, 1894. John Lay to J.W. Hardin
    May 23, 1894. P. Levyson to J.W. Hardin
    Jun 22, 1894. [Thom Lay] to J.W. Hardin
    Aug 4, 1894. J.P. Randle to J.W. Hardin
    Aug 10, 1894. E.F. Schlikeisen to State of Texas
    Aug 16, 1894. J.B. Ashe to J.W. Hardin
    Aug 22, 1894. J.W. Hardin to J. Buchanan
    Aug 23, 1894. J.B. Ashe to J.W. Hardin
    Sept 11, 1894. Charles Reuter to [Unknown]
    Sept 15, 1894. Gilbert Book Co. to D. Cobb
    Sept 20, 1894. J.B. Ashe to J.W. Hardin
    Sept 28, 1894. Gilbert Book Co. to J.W. Hardin
    Oct 3, 1894. John Taylor to J.W. Hardin
    Oct 4, 1894. J.W. Hardin to J. Clements
    Oct 4, 1894. Mary Barnett to J.W. Hardin
    Oct 6, 1894. M. Blackburn to J.W. Hardin
    Oct 7, 1894. Louis Auguero to J.W. Hardin
    Oct 7, 1894. Roman Auguero to M. Merrdosa
    Oct 8, 1894. Louis Auguero to [J.W. Hardin]
    Oct 13, 1894. La Opinion Del Pueblo, Vol. 1 No. 2[unknown] [J.W. Hardin] to The People of Gonzalez County
    Oct 15, 1894. M.L. West to J.W. Hardin
    Oct 17, 1894. R.M. Glover to [Unknown]
    Oct 20, 1894. Frank Kelso to R.R. Coleman
    Oct 21, 1894. J.F. Wingate to J.W. Hardin
    Oct 21, 1894. Frank Howell to R. Coleman
    Oct 22, 1894. B. Bratton to J.W. Hardin
    Oct 27, 1894. F.B. Houston to J.W. Hardin
    Oct 27, 1894. J. Denson to State of Texas
    [unknown] [Denson] to [Unknown]
    Oct 28, 1894. N. Witt to J.W. Hardin
    Oct 29, 1894. F. Diedrich to [Kotzel]
    [unknown] [D.C. Price] to [Unknown]
    Nov 1, 1894. R.B. Hudson to State of Texas
    Nov 1, 1894. S.H. Cresap to State of Texas
    Nov 2, 1894. R.R. Coleman to J.W. Hardin
    Nov 3, 1894. W.E. Jones to Voters of Gonzales
    [unknown] [Unknown] to [Unknown]
    Nov 20, 1894. O.P. Krueger to Joe Barbisch
    Dec 1, 1894. R.M. Glover to J.W. Hardin
    Dec 16, 1894. Marriage certificate for Charles Billings and Mollie Hardin
    Dec 30, 1894. Callie Lewis to J.W. Hardin
  - 1895 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Jan 11, 1895. P.M. Smith to J.W. Hardin
    Jan 14, 1895. A.O. Hamon & Co. to J.W. Hardin
    Jan 18, 1895. [Unknown] to J.W. Hardin
    Jan 23, 1895. Capt. Lewis to J.W. Hardin
    Jan 26, 1895. [Unknown] to J.W. Hardin[unknown] J.B. Miller to [J.W. Hardin] [Attached] [unknown] [Martin Hardin] to J.W. Hardin
    Feb 5, 1895. Annie Lewis to [Unknown]
    Feb 5, 1895. [A.D. Weston] to J.W. Hardin
    Feb 10, 1895. [J.D. Hargis] to J.W. Hardin
    Feb 12, 1895. J.B. Miller to J.W. Hardin[unknown] Blank check from The Pecos Valley Bank
    Feb 22, 1895. W.C. McGown to J.W. Hardin[unknown] Blank office form of U.S. Bateman
    Feb 28, 1895. W.H. Smith to J.W. Hardin
    Mar 4, 1895. Capt. Lewis to J.W. Hardin
    Mar 4, 1895. Bettie Lewis to J.W. Hardin
    Mar 6, 1895. Samuel Glover to J.W. Hardin
    Mar 6, 1895. J.H. Clements to J.W. Hardin
    Mar 23, 1895. Capt. Lewis to J.W. Hardin[unknown] Business card of J.W. Hardin
    Apr 6, 1895. Felipe Leijas to [Unknown]
    Apr 15, 1895. [Unknown] to J.W. Hardin
    May 27, 1895. Injunction Writ [Unknown] to [Unknown]
    [unknown] Affidavit for change of venue[unknown] F.B. Simmons to [Unknown]
    [Jun 2, 1895] [Unknown] to J.W. Hardin
    [Jun 3, 1895] [D.L. Kemp] to J.W. Hardin
    Jun 16, 1895. W.D. Allison to J.W. Hardin
    [Jun 18, 1895] R.M. Glover to J.W. Hardin
    Jul 11, 1895. J.H. Flynh to J.W. Hardin & [Unknown] to J.H. Flynh
    Jul 7, 1895. A.G. Weston to J.W. Hardin
    Jul 28, 1895. J.D. Hargis to J.W. Hardin[unknown]
    Envelopes
- Law School Notes, 1886-1889, undated
  Series Description
  This series contains hand-written legal exams and papers.
  - Law School Notes (Box 2, Folder 1)
    "Questions on contracts and Sales Junior Law Class Jan 25, 1887"
    "Different Actions at Common Law, and what recoverable byeach"
    "Review Questions [on 4 Blackstone]"
    "Examination in Blackstone '84 O.M. Roberts"
    "Chief Justices of The Republic of Texas from 1836 to 1845"
    "Feb 1884"
    "Questions on Contracts & Sales 1885"
    "No. 64""Final Examination, June 6th 1886"
    "Questions for the Senior Law Class, 30th Jan., 1889."
    "Questions for the Junior Law Class"
    "Junior Law Class 'Examination by O.M. Roberts' Feb 4 1886"
    "Junior Law Class 'O.M. Roberts' not exact questions but boiled down"
    "University of Texas Examination of the Junior Law Class, by O.M. Roberts, Professor, January 29, 1887"
    "Examination Questions in Blackstone"
    "[Provided] by O.M. Roberts Questions for Junior law class"
    "Manslaughter is the unlawful killing"
    "University of Texas. Law Department. February 4th, 1889."
    "University of Texas. Law Department. February 5th, 1889."
    "Second Semi-Annual Report of Upsilon Chapter of Sigma Nu"
    "Sample Pages of Early Laws of Texas"
    "Precedents and Rules of Pleading in Civil Actions"
    "Sample Pages A treatise on the Civil Jurisdiction"
    "Catalogue Gilbert Book Co. Saint Louis"
- Family Correspondence and Memorabilia, 1897-1931, undated
  This series contains Hardin family correspondence and other memorabilia.
  - Family Correspondence and Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 2)
    "Why Do You Swear?" signed by J.W. HardinPages from a small notebook, unsigned and undated
    Pages from a small notebook, unsigned and undated
    Invitation card for F.H. Cobb
    Hotel-Charco advertisement
    Iron City National Bank advertisement
    Harper Illustrating Syndicate advertisement
    The American Monthly Review of Reviews promotion dated December 14, 1897
    London Crayon Portrait Co. promotion
    Receipt of purchase from Fred Diedrich
    "Flirtation poetry" by J.B. Cainey
    "Programme"
    Loose pages from a pocket Bible
    [Oct 20, unknown][May Hardin] to John Hardin
    Marriage license for John W Hardin and Lily Hause
    "The Language System of Penmanship"
    [Apr 15, unknown] J.B. Cobb to John Hardin
    Jan 17, 1902. [Unknown] to John Hardin
    Oct 17, 1910. [Unknown] to John Hardin
    Nov 2, 1931. W.B. Teagarden to Mrs. Charles Billings
- Newspaper Articles, 1894-1950, undated
  This series contains clippings that relate to Hardin.
  - Newspaper Articles (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Jan 1, [unknown]. "Hardin on Trial"
    Jan 1, [unknown]. "Hardin on Trial"[Photocopy]
    [unknown] "Pleading For Pardon"[Photocopy]
    [Sept 17, 1894] [The Semi-Weekly Drag Net][Photocopy]
    Oct 13, 1894. Waelder Local.
    [Oct 11, 1894] [The Gonzales Inquirer][Photocopy]
    Oct 12, 1894. [The Semi-Weekly Drag Net][Photocopy]
    Oct 13, 1894. La Opinion Del Pueblo.[Photocopy]
    Oct 13, 1894. [The Gonzales Inquirer][Photocopy]
    Oct 25, 1894. The Semi-Weekly Drag Net.[Photocopy]
    Oct 23, 1894. [The Gonzales Inquirer][Photocopy]
    [Nov 1, 1894] [The Semi-Weekly Drag Net][Photocopy]
    [Nov 1, 1894] [The Gonzales Inquirer][Photocopy]
    Nov 2, 1894. The Semi-Weekly Drag Net.[Photocopy]
    [Jan 9, 1895] [The Kimble County Citizen][Photocopy]
    [Apr 24, 1895] [El Paso Daily Tribune][Photocopy]
    May 4, 1895. The Evening Tribune.[Photocopy]
    June 13, 1895. The Evening Tribune.[Photocopy]
    Mar 3, 1930. The San Antonio Light.[Photocopy]
    Feb 8, 1937. The San Antonio Light.[Photocopy]
    Feb 24, 1938. Kerrville Mountain Sun.[Photocopy]
    Jan 8, 1950. "Soft-hearted." The American Weekly.[Photocopy]
- Photographs, circa 1873-1887, undated
  This series contains photographs of Hardin's family, many of the subjects are identified.
  - circa 1873-1877, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    John Wesley Hardin. c. 1873 [Photo reproduction]
    Jane Bowen Hardin. c. 1885 [Tintype]
    Jane Bowen Hardin. c. 1885 [Photo reproduction]
    Jane Bowen Hardin and Molly. c. 1887 [Tintype]
    Jane Bowen Hardin and Molly. c. 1887 [Photo reproduction]
    Elizabeth Cobb. undated [Tintype]
    Elizabeth Cobb. undated [Photo reproduction]
    Bright Smith. undated [Tintype]
    Bright Smith. undated [Photo reproduction]
    Aunt Matt. undated [Albumen Print]
    Joe Hardin. undated [Albumen Print]
    Joe Hardin. undated [Photo reproduction]
    Grandma Odim. undated [Tintype]
    M. Lacey and son, J.W.H. undated [Tintype]
    M. Lacey and son, J.W.H. undated [Photo reproduction]
    John Wesley Hardin, Jr. undated [Albumen Print]
    John Wesley Hardin, Jr. undated [Photo reproduction]
    John Wesley Hardin, Jr. undated [Photo reproduction
  - undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Molly Hardin Billings. [Albumen Print]
    Molly Hardin Billings. [Photo reproduction]
    Victory, Otis, Edith, and Blanch Billings. [Albumen Print]
    Victory, Otis, Edith, and Blanch Billings. [Photo reproduction]
    John Lyons. [Albumen Print]
    John Lyons. [Photo reproduction]
    Jennie Hardin Lyons.[Albumen Print]
    Jennie Hardin Lyons. [Photo reproduction]
    Jennie and Allie Lyons. [Albumen Print]
    Matt Bowen. [Platinotype]
    Matt Bowen. [Photo reproduction]
    Benny Bowen. [Albumen Print]
    Benny Bowen. [Photo reproduction]
    Brown Bowen and Black Tom Caffole. [Tintype]
    Brown Bowen and Black Tom Caffole. [Photo reproduction]
    Josh Bowen. [Tintype]
    Josh Bowen. [Photo reproduction]
  - 1878-1879, 1895, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Contents
    Mr. Witte. undated [Albumen Print]
    Mr. Witte. undated [Photo reproduction]
    Nan Witte. undated [Albumen Print]
    Jim Clements. undated [Tintype]
    Jim Clements. undated [Photo reproduction]
    Manning Clements. undated [Photo reproduction]
    Joe Clements. undated [Tintype]
    John Wesley Hardin on slab. 1895 [Photo reproduction]
    Information regarding. 1895. [Photo reproduction]
    Information regarding. 1895 [Photo reproduction]
    John Selman. 1878 [Photo reproduction]
    Captain John Armstrong. undated [Photo reproduction]
    Jan 9, 1879. J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin [Photo reproduction]
  - undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Pierre Adolph Beasley. [Albumen Print]
    Pierre Adolph Beasley. [Photo reproduction]
    Mrs. Helen Bulah M'Rose. [Photo reproduction]
    [Rudolph Billings] [Tintype]
    [Rudolph Billings] [Photo reproduction]
    [Unknown] [Albumen Print]
    [Unknown] [Photo reproduction]
    [Unknown and Unknown] [Albumen Print]
    [Unknown] [Tintype]
    [Unknown and Unknown] [Tintype]
    [Unknown] [Tintype
  - Negatives (Box 2, Folder 8)
- John Wesley Hardin Collection Use Files
  - A-M (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - P (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - R-Z (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Photocopied Correspondence
  This collection contains the reference photocopies of the Hardin correspondence.
  - Photocopied Correspondence (Box 3)